Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-kullback-388b9241 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Statistics
Data Analysis
Regression Analysis

Languages

English

Certifications

Alteryx Core Certified Intermediate Python for Data Science

Honors-Awards
Dean's List

Kevin Kullback

Sr. Data Scientist at Alteryx
Orange County, California Area

Summary

I graduated with a M.S. in Statistics from San Diego State University and I also a B.S. in Mathematics and minor in Statistics from California State University, Monterey Bay.

I currently work as a Sr. Data Scientist at Alteryx working on predictive models for the sales organization like Churn modeling and Opporutnity Scoring. Before Alteryx, I was a Data Science, Senior Analyst at Mavenlink focusing on Churn and usage analytics.

While working as Customer Support Workforce Analyst at (mt) Media Temple, I created multiple Tableau dashboards allowing the President, Director of CS, and Managers of CS to view key metrics. Some of the metrics include chat or call volumes, Service Level Agreement, Utilization of the agents, and Productivity of the agents. I was also in charge of forecasting call and chat volumes as well as handle times in 15 minute intervals to get staffing requirements so we can increase SLA.

Before (mt), I worked at the San Diego County Regional Airport Authority as a graduate intern. I worked for two different departments in my year and 9 months of time there. I worked on different data analysis projects that included analysis of a customer service survey and impact of Uber and Lyft on taxi and parking revenues.

I'm always interested in any job offerings, training or learning opportunities in my various interests, please feel free to contact me.

Experience

Alteryx
Sr. Data Scientist
September 2019 - Present (7 months)
Orange County, California Area

Mavenlink

2 years 7 months

Senior Data Science Analyst February 2019 - September 2019 (8 months)

Irvine, California

Data Science Analyst

February 2018 - February 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Orange County, California Area

Data Analyst

March 2017 - February 2018 (1 year)

Orange County, California Area

- Created R Studio Shiny dashboards to track pipeline generation and sales forecasts
- Helped evaluate and implement InsightSquared to the Sales team and Slate for the rest of the company
- Worked on updating a health score for current clients by using Logistic Regression
- Created a R Studio Shiny dashboard to help the product team see feature requests from prospects and clients
- Helped forecast won deals from the Partner Sales channel

Media Temple CS Workforce Analyst July 2016 - March 2017 (9 months)

Greater Los Angeles Area

- Created Tableau dashboards for reporting of calls and chats for Volume,
 SLA, and Handle Time.
- Created Tableau dashboards for reporting of various agent metrics, e.g.,
 Utilization and Productivity
- Created Tableau dashboards to track volume and completion time of different CloudTech services such as website migration and restorations
- Created volume forecasting using time series analysis for capacity planning and staffing in 15-minute intervals
- Ran different SQL queries for Customer Support reports as well as Customer Success reports of 4-star clients

San Diego County Regional Airport Authority Data Analysis Intern October 2014 - June 2016 (1 year 9 months)

- Ground Transportation
- o Used analysis to find impact of telecommunications network companies (TNCs) on Taxis dispatches, Taxi cost recovery fee, Parking transactions, and Parking revenues
- o Created regression models to predict Taxis or Parking based on Enplanements and TNCs
- o Helped on reducing wait times for Rental Car Center shuttles by using logistic regression
- Airport Service Quality Survey in partnership with Talent, Culture, and Capability (TCC) Intelligence and Planning
- o Established analytical procedures
- o Supported discussions with internal Stakeholders and initiation of action plans
- Concessions Marketing Survey in partnership with Terminals & Tenants
- o Created, conducted, analyzed, and reported results
- HR Metrics
- o Improved TCC Impact metrics
- o Provided analysis on quality of hire survey data
- o Oversight of retirement metrics
- o Assumed analysis of Leading at All Levels correlation between graduation and promotion

ASAP, CSUMB

Tutor

August 2012 - May 2014 (1 year 10 months)

Seaside, CA

- Tutored students in Discrete Mathematics and Pre-Calculus
- Held tutoring sessions of 6 to 30 students
- · Provided different strategies to enhance learning
- ITTPC Level 1 Certified

Education

San Diego State University

Master's Degree, Statistics (2014 - 2016)

California State University-Monterey Bay Bachelor's Degree, Mathematics · (2010 - 2014)

El Camino Real High School

· (2006 - 2010)